Guide to the International Brotherhood of Teamsters Canadian Conference records 1955-1989 IBT0026
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
IBT Canadian Conference Records
1955-1989
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America
Teamsters Canada
IBT0026
0.25 Linear Feet
This collection contains proceedings and pulications of the Canadian Conference of Teamsters. The material dates from 1955-1989. These are the records of the Canadian Conference of Teamsters, a regional governance body in the structure of the International Brotherhood of Teamsters.
Arrangement
Organized into 2 series: Proceedings and Publications
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains proceedings and pulications of the Canadian Conference of Teamsters. The material dates from 1955-1989. These are the records of the Canadian Conference of Teamsters, a regional governance body in the structure of the International Brotherhood of Teamsters.
Biographical / Historical
Within the International Brotherhood of Teamsters, between 1937 and 1995, members of the union met and exchanged ideas on a regional basis. These regional organizations were called Area Conferences. In the U.S. there were four area Area Conferences: the Western Conference of Teamsters formed in 1937, the Southern Conference of Teamsters formed in 1944, the Central States Conference of teamster formed in 1953, and the Eastern Conference of Teamsters also formed in 1953. Canadian Teamsters had their own Canadian Conference of Teamsters, known today as Teamsters Canada. Area Conferences met annually to discuss general issues facing the IBT and to hold discussion more directly relevant to IBT Trade Divisions: contract negotiations, organizing campaigns, workplace disputes, etc. For example, when the Central States Conference met, after the general sessions, delegates would meet based on the trades they represented: the brewery and soft drink delegates coming together, cannery delegates coming together, dairy delegates coming together, etc. In this way, the IBT was strengthened in terms of both national and regional coordination of efforts. The Area Conferences came under criticism during the General Presidency of Ron Carey. Making the argument that they were redundant and wasteful, Carey disbanded them in 1995.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the International Brotherhood of Teamsters
Canada; Conferences; Labor; Labor unions; Labor unions -- Canada -- History; International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America
- Proceedings, 1955-1958; Series 1; 0.25 Linear Feet
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains the proceedings of the Candian Conference of Teamsters annual meetings from 1955-1958 and includes.
  - Canadian Conference of Teamsters Proceedings of the 2nd Conference, 4-5 June 1955; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Canadian Conference of Teamsters Proceedings of the 3rd Conference, 28-29 April 1956; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Canadian Conference of Teamsters Proceedings of the 5th Conference, 19-20 April 1958; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Publications, 1966-1989; Series 2; 0.25 Linear Feet
  This series contains the publications of the Candian Conference of Teamsters annual meetings from 1966-1989 and includes a steward's manual and pamphlets distributed at meetings.
  - Canadian Conference of Teamsters Steward's Manual, November 1989; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Teamsters Canada, November 1966; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Craig McInnes Member Dues Card and Correspondence, 1959-2013 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Teamsters Canada Brochure, Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - The Most Powerful Union in Canada Brochure, ND; IBT0026 Series 2 (Box SHARED Box 31, Folder 8)